<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
  <Recipe id="1" name="One pot creamy tomato beef pasta" prepTime="00:10:00" cookTime="00:20:00" yield="4 servings" url="https://www.recipetineats.com/wprm_print/one-pot-creamy-tomato-beef-pasta">
    <Ingredient measurement="TableSpoon" quantity="1.5" for="">olive oil</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="Unit" quantity="2" for="">garlic cloves</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="Unit" quantity="1" for="">onion</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="Gram" quantity="500" for="">beef mince / ground beef</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="TeaSpoon" quantity="2" for="">Italian herbs</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="TableSpoon" quantity="2" for="">tomato paste</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="Gram" quantity="400" for="">can crushed tomatoes</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="TeaSpoon" quantity="0.5" for="">red pepper flakes</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="TeaSpoon" quantity="1.5" for="">cooking salt/kosher salt</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="TeaSpoon" quantity="0.5" for="">black pepper</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="Unit" quantity="1" for="">chicken stock/broth</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="Gram" quantity="350" for="">fusilli, penne, elbow macaroni</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="Cup" quantity="0.75" for="">thickened / heavy cream</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="Unit" quantity="1" for="Serving">Parmesan cheese</Ingredient>
    <Ingredient measurement="Unit" quantity="1" for="Serving">Parsley</Ingredient>
    <Instruction>Sauté - Heat the oil on high heat in a large heavy-based pot. Cook garlic and onion for 1 1/2 minutes.</Instruction>
    <Instruction>Cook beef &amp; seasonings - Add beef and cook, breaking it up as you go, until you can no longer see red meat. Add the Italian herbs and cook for 30 seconds, then add tomato paste and cook for 1 minute to cook out the raw flavour.</Instruction>
    <Instruction>All in - Add crushed tomato, chicken stock, salt, pepper and red pepper flakes, if using. Stir, then add the pasta.</Instruction>
    <Instruction>Cook 15 min - Bring the liquid to a simmer, then cook for 15 minutes, stirring every couple of minutes then more frequently towards the end (ensure pasta doesn't stick to base) until the pasta is just about cooked.</Instruction>
    <Instruction>Creamy - Add cream, then simmer for a further 1 to 2 minutes. It will still be quite saucy - this is what you want! Pasta absorbs liquid quickly, so it will still be nice and oozy when you start eating.</Instruction>
    <Instruction>Serve - Remove from the stove. Give it a good stir then ladle into bowls. Serve with parmesan and parsley.</Instruction>
    <Note>1. Italian Herbs - Just a store bought mix, very common at grocery stores. If you don't have any, just use a mix of dried oregano, parsley, basil. Or sub with a teaspoon of Worcestershire sauce.</Note>
    <Note>2. Chicken stock/broth - Tastier than water! I stock up when on sale. Economical alternative - I recommend using Vegeta stock powder (info here - I use it regularly) or Chinese chicken stock powder (Knorr) plus water. I prefer the flavour of these over other Western stock powders. </Note>
    <Note>3. Any short pasta will work here, like macaroni, penne etc but not tiny ones like risoni/orzo. If using long pasta, easiest to break in half and you can cook about 400g/14oz (a little more than short pasta).</Note>
    <Note>4. Leftovers will keep for 3 days in the fridge. Not suitable for freezing.</Note>
    <Note>Nutrition per serving, assuming 5 servings using 90% lean beef.</Note>
  </Recipe>
</root>